

Sylvia Tadross Lead UI Developer

Contact

sylvia.adel.emil@gmail.com



(0700598158



Frejavägen 23, 174 46 Sundbyberg, Sweden

Hard Skills

- HTML/ CSS
- HTML5/CSS3
- SASS
- Bootstrap
- · Responsive Design
- Angular/Angular JS
- React
- VUF JS
- JavaScript
- JQUERY
- TypeScript
- Angular CLI, NPM
- GIT, TFS, SVN
- · Atlassian Jira
- Material UI (React and Angular)
- .NET(ASPX Web Forms, MVC)
- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- Adobe XD adept
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Figma
- Whimsical

Education Background

- Ain Shams University Cairo, Egypt **Bachelor Computer and Information** Sciences Completed in 2012
- Frontend Trainee, Novare. Sweden October 2022- present

Key responsibilities:

- Created a react app from scratch with all UI and functionality features.
- Responsible for creating seven other react projects in six months.

About Me

Creative UI Developer with 8 years facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software. Maintains user-centric designs while adhering to prescribed interface principals and related development goals. Dedicated to creating inviting and unintimidating interfaces for everything from simple open-source applications to complex proprietary systems.

Professional Experience

Lead UI developer, ITWorx. Cairo, Egypt 01/2020 - 10/2022

Key responsibilities:

- Oversaw troubleshooting of technical issues to solve problems within a reasonable timeframe.
- · Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement.
- Redesigned website to increase traffic, applying SEO techniques to improve Google ranking.
- Started and applied designs for new websites using Angular and
- Responsible for supporting style enhancements in all projects in Syngenta Account with new technologies like Angular, React and
- Migrated websites using latest versions of Bootstarp and Angular.

Senior UI developer, ITWorx. Cairo, Egypt 05/2018 - 12/2019

Key responsibilities:

- Created a new framework like bootstrap named 'Nebula' using html and sass to be applied Itworx HUB.
- Enhanced sass code on Adsec website (React.js), assisted frontend developers in tasks and adding clean code

Senior UI Developer, Intelisc. Cairo, Egypt 02/2017 - 05/2018

Key responsibilities:

- Started a new mobile application and applied all psd files using
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Developed Application UIs via emerging Front End Technologies such as Angular.
- Took and edited photographs to use in digital publications, websites and social media.
- Tested websites at different design and production stages to assess conformance with designs.
- Researched and proposed new solutions to make the application more user-friendly

UI Developer, Link Development. Cairo, Egypt 02/2015 - 02/2017

Key responsibilities:

- Changing the layout of some pages in orange.com.
- Converting PSD files to web pages using HTML and CSS

Freelance UI Developer, Q8Soft. Cairo, Egypt 01/2016 - 12/2016

Key responsibilities:

• Enhanced the design of http://www.dynamscan.com and http://www.printjobprocessing.com.

Product Support Engineer, Link Development. Cairo, Egypt 01/2013 - 02/2015

Key responsibilities:

- Worked directly with clients to achieve result. Supports editing content of orange.com using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery.
- Using SharePoint designer in changing some styles.

Languages

- Arabic: Native language
- English: Proficient
 French: Intermedia
- French: Intermediate
- · Swedish: Beginner

Social Contact

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sylvia-tadross-710b9597
- https://github.com/sylviaadel
- A https://portfolio-571e7.web.app/

References are available upon request